

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENCE

# Details

0822 3427 8915 ahmadreys@gmail.com Jember – Jawa Timur

# Links

**Web Portfolio** 

**Blog** 

LinkedIn

Instagram

**Github** 

## **Hobbies**

- Football
- Badminton
- Reading
- Games

# Languages

English Indonesian Intermediate Native

# **Profile**

I am interested in data science and web and mobile application development. From this interest, I have work experience in the field of data science, namely as an ETL Developer in a banking company for more than a year. Apart from being in the field of Data Science, I have experience worked as a web and mobile application developer. I am a fast learner and easy to adapt to a new environment.

# **Employment History**

### IT Staff, PT Cita Mineral Investindo (Harita Group) Tbk, Jakarta

July 2021 - Present

My role in this position as IT Staff that developed **ERP system** for company using **Laravel, React Native and PostgreSQL**. Beside it, I also support to other department to **maintain IT Infrastructure**. Develop **mobile application for HR Department** using **React Native** and **Laravel Lumen**.

# ETL Developer, PT Bumi Amartha Teknologi Mandiri, Jakarta

October 2019 - October 2020

My role in this position as a **Regla Team**, actually implementation IFRS9 (International Financial Reporting Standard 9) in **BCA Multifinance**. In this project I **used SQL Server, Oracle DB for database and Microsoft SSIS** for the data flow process.

# Web Developer, PT Panca Prima, Surabaya

May 2019 - August 2019

My role is as a web developer to build **ERP applications** for real estate companies. Here I use **the laravel framework** to build the application.

### Mobile Developer Intern, PT Itematik Pramitha Nusantara, Yogyakarta

March 2019 - June 2019

My role in this position is to develop **point of sale (POS)** mobile apps. Using **Flutter Framework** as front end mobile. **Laravel Framework** as Back End API to send data to UI.

### IT Staff Intern, UPTI Universitas Jember, Jember

Jan 2014 - May 2014

My role in this position is to develop **web application using wordpress and Yii Framework**. Beside that, my task is to **maintain internet and intranet networking** in campus environment.

# Education

### Bachelor Informatics Engineering, Politeknik Negeri Jember, Jember

September 2015 - July 2019

Software Engineering, SMK Negeri 8 Jember, Jember

June 2012 - June 2015

# **Personal Project**

### Point Of Sales Mobile Application, Yogyakarta

March 2019 - June 2019

Mobile Cashier Application Develop With Flutter And Laravel Framework

# Sentiment Analysis On PT Kereta Api Indonesia Social Media, Jember

July 2018 - December 2018

Customer Sentiment On PT KAI Social Media.

#### NilaiGizi.com, Jember

June 2018 - September 2018

Information Of Product Nutrition Website.

### AhliGizi.id, Jember

January 2018 - June 2018

A Nutrition Consultant Website Platform

## Skills

### **Data Engineer**

I have experience work in data engineer especially as a ETL Developer Using Microsof SSIS, SSRS, SQL Server and Oracle DB. I have learn about Hive, Spark, Hadoop from Cloudera to organize data. And I have learnt how to use NoSQL db using CouchDB and MongoDB.

### **Web Development**

I have worked on some project as a web developer using Laravel, Code Igniter, and Vue. Actually in web development using some programming language such as HTML, PHP, Javascript and Mysql. In web development I have worked on some database to save data using Mysql, SQL Server and PostgreSQL.

#### **Mobile Development**

I have experience to develop mobile application using React Native and Flutter.

### Design

In my spare time I like to use my time to design UI/UX such as **Mobile Apps, Website, and Social Media**. I usually use **Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD and Figma to design**.

### **Data Science**

I have done my research about **sentiment analysis** on PT Kereta Api Indonesia Twitter account using **Python, Pandas**. I have learned how to use **Tableau, Microsoft Excel and Power BI** to Analyze data.

# Certifications

Desktop Application Training Professional Level, e-biz Microsoft Partner

December 2018

**Database Administrator, BNSP** 

October 2018

Test Of English for International Proficiency, Ednovation International

July 2019

## Courses

Business Sentiment Analysis Using Python, Data Science Indonesia

September 2018

Become a Data Engineer: Mastering the Concepts, LinkedIn Learning

November 2020

The Data Science Course Bootcamp 2020, Udemy

November 2020

React - The Complete Guide, Udemy

November 2020

# Competitions

Kamadjaja Hackathon Day, Kamadjaja Logistics - Surabaya

November 2018

Coding Competition, Politeknik Negeri Jember

October 2018

Google Firebase AppFest Hackathon 2017 Indonesia, Google - Jakarta

September 2017

Gerakan Nasional 1000 StartUp, Kominfo - Surabaya

August 2017

## **Link Accounts**

Web Portfolio - https://bit.ly/RisgiPortfolio

Blog - https://bit.ly/RisqiBlog

LinkedIn - <a href="https://bit.ly/RisqiLinkedIn">https://bit.ly/RisqiLinkedIn</a>

Instagram - https://bit.ly/RisqiInstagram

Github - https://bit.ly/RisqiGithub